Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Katherine and today we're talking about fear.
我是Katherine，今天我们要聊聊恐惧。
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going to talk about phobias, different types of fears that you have.
今天我们要讨论恐惧症，也就是你们有的各种不同类型的恐惧。
Many people are scared of different things and that's what we're going to talk about
很多人都害怕不同的东西，这就是我们今天要聊的
today.
内容。
Okay, so let's listen to today's dialogue and find out what the people in our dialogue
好，那我们先来听今天的对话，看看对话里的人
are very, very afraid of.
非常非常害怕什么。
Are you excited about your trip next month?
你对下个月的旅行感到兴奋吗？
Yes and no.
又兴奋又不兴奋。
I can't wait to go to Europe, but at the same time I'm terrified.
我迫不及待想去欧洲，但同时我又很害怕。
Why?
为什么？
Well, I have aerophobia.
嗯，我有飞行恐惧症。
I have a chronic fear of flying.
我对坐飞机有长期的恐惧。
Oh really?
哦，真的吗？
I have an uncle who is also terrified of flying.
我有个叔叔也特别害怕坐飞机。
It's not that bad though.
不过也没那么糟吧。
I mean, it is pretty scary to be up in this big machine flying through the air at 700
我是说，坐在这个大机器里，以每小时700英里的速度在空中飞行，
miles per hour.
确实挺吓人的。
I actually have arachnophobia.
我其实有蜘蛛恐惧症。
You're scared of spiders?
你怕蜘蛛？
I actually have two more phobias, acrophobia and glossophobia.
我其实还有两种恐惧症：恐高症和演讲恐惧症。
I guess that explains why you're afraid of flying, but public speaking is not that bad.
我猜这解释了为什么你害怕坐飞机，但公开演讲没那么糟吧。
Are you kidding?
你在开玩笑吗？
When I get on stage, my palms start to sweat.
我一上台，手心就开始出汗。
I get really nervous and I can hardly speak.
我变得非常紧张，几乎说不出话来。
Well, I must confess that I am a bit claustrophobic.
嗯，我得承认我有点幽闭恐惧症。
I hate being in an elevator for more than five seconds.
我讨厌在电梯里待超过五秒钟。
We are such weirdos, right?
我们真是怪人，对吧？
All right, we're back, so let's take a look at those phobias on Language Takeaway.
好了，我们回来了，现在来看看“语言小贴士”里的那些恐惧症。
Language Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
The first phobia that we have is called aerophobia.
第一个恐惧症叫做飞行恐惧症。
That's right, aerophobia.
没错，飞行恐惧症。
That means that you are scared of flying.
意思是你害怕坐飞机。
We can tell because phobia means fear of something, but it's not just a fear.
我们可以看出来，因为“phobia”意味着对某事的恐惧，但这不仅仅是普通的害怕。
It means that if you go on an airplane, you get very, very upset.
它意味着如果你上飞机，你会非常非常不安。
You think that you're going to die.
你会觉得自己要死了。
Phobia is a very serious fear, but aero, like aeroplane, is the prefix.
恐惧症是一种非常严重的恐惧，而“aero”就像“aeroplane”一样，是前缀。
Phobia is a fear of going on airplanes.
恐惧症就是对坐飞机的恐惧。
That's right.
没错。
Another phobia that we have is arachnophobia.
另一个恐惧症是蜘蛛恐惧症。
Again, as you see in the prefix, arachno is related to a spider.
同样，如你在前缀中看到的，“arachno”与蜘蛛有关。
That's right.
没错。
This comes from the origins of English.
这来源于英语的起源。
I'm not sure if it's Greek or Latin, but arachnophobia, like arachnid, has to do with spiders.
我不确定是希腊语还是拉丁语，但蜘蛛恐惧症，像“arachnid”一样，与蜘蛛有关。
I'm afraid of spiders if I have arachnophobia.
如果我有蜘蛛恐惧症，我就害怕蜘蛛。
That is right.
没错。
Now taking a look at two more types of phobias here, we have acrophobia and glossophobia.
现在来看另外两种恐惧症：恐高症和演讲恐惧症。
Let's take a look at the first one, acrophobia.
先看第一个，恐高症。
Acrophobia has to do with heights.
恐高症与高度有关。
I don't like to be on tall buildings.
我不喜欢在高楼上。
I don't like to maybe look down from heights.
我可能不喜欢从高处往下看。
That means I'm afraid of heights.
这意味着我恐高。
That's right.
没错。
You're afraid of being at a very high altitude, acrophobia.
你害怕处于很高的海拔，就是恐高症。
Now glossophobia is an interesting one because this one, you are scared of public speaking
演讲恐惧症则很有趣，因为这种恐惧症是害怕公开演讲，
or you get very nervous when you're in front of a group of people.
或者当你在人群面前时会非常紧张。
Right.
对。
So this is actually a very, very common fear, but if it's a serious fear, it's a phobia.
所以这其实是一种非常常见的恐惧，但如果很严重，就成了恐惧症。
So glossophobia means that when you go in front of people, you get very, very anxious,
所以演讲恐惧症意味着当你面对人群时，你会非常非常焦虑、
upset, your stomach hurts, you have wet hands.
不安，胃疼，手心出汗。
So that's a very serious fear.
所以这是一种非常严重的恐惧。
That's right.
没错。
And for our last phobia, we have claustrophobia.
最后一个恐惧症是幽闭恐惧症。
I think it's one of the most common ones.
我觉得这是最常见的一种。
If you have claustrophobia, you're afraid of smaller tight spaces.
如果你有幽闭恐惧症，你害怕狭小封闭的空间。
That's right.
没错。
So people who, so you heard the word claustrophobic, people who are claustrophobic or people who
所以人们——你听到了“claustrophobic”这个词，有幽闭恐惧症的人或
suffer from claustrophobia don't like to be in small tight places like elevators, for
患有幽闭恐惧症的人不喜欢待在狭小封闭的地方，比如电梯，
example, tunnels.
或者隧道。
So now you brought up an interesting point.
所以你现在提出了一个有趣的点。
Our last phobia, we said claustrophobic and now we must make the difference between, for
最后一个恐惧症，我们说了“claustrophobic”，现在我们必须区分，比如，
example, claustrophobia and being claustrophobic.
“claustrophobia”和“claustrophobic”的区别。
So a phobia, you hear the word, you hear the ending IA, phobia, claustrophobia is a noun.
所以“phobia”，你听到这个词，结尾是IA，“phobia”，“claustrophobia”是名词。
That means I can talk about, I have it, I have this fear.
这意味着我可以谈论它，我有它，我有这种恐惧。
But when you're talking about the adjective, something that describes you, you would have
但当你用形容词来描述自己时，你需要用
to use the ic ending.
IC结尾。
I'm claustrophobic.
我有幽闭恐惧症。
He is acrophobic.
他有恐高症。
They are aerophobic.
他们有飞行恐惧症。
Okay, so that is the adjective form.
好的，所以那是形容词形式。
So if I say I have arachnophobia, it means I have this fear or I can say I am arachnophobic.
所以如果我说我有蜘蛛恐惧症，意思是我有这种恐惧，或者我可以说我是蜘蛛恐惧症患者。
Great.
太好了。
So this can be used for all other kinds of phobias.
所以这可以用于所有其他类型的恐惧症。
So when you learn those words, remember that there's two different kinds.
所以当你学习这些词时，记住有两种不同的形式。
There's the IA, there's the IA, a phobia, which is the noun and ic, which is the adjective.
有 IA，有 IA，phobia 是名词，ic 是形容词。
All right.
好的。
Let's listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit with Fluency Builder.
让我们再听一遍对话，稍后我们会回来进行流利度训练。
Are you excited about your trip next month?
你对下个月的旅行感到兴奋吗？
Yes and no.
又兴奋又不兴奋。
I can't wait to go to Europe, but at the same time, I'm terrified.
我迫不及待想去欧洲，但同时我又很害怕。
Why?
为什么？
Well, I have aerophobia.
嗯，我有飞行恐惧症。
I have a chronic fear of flying.
我有慢性的飞行恐惧。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
I have an uncle who is also terrified of flying.
我有个叔叔也害怕飞行。
It's not that bad though.
不过也没那么糟。
I mean, it is pretty scary to be up in this big machine flying through the air at 700
我的意思是，坐在这个大机器里以每小时700英里的速度在空中飞行确实挺吓人的。
miles per hour.
英里每小时。
I actually have arachnophobia.
我其实有蜘蛛恐惧症。
You're scared of spiders?
你害怕蜘蛛？
I actually have two more phobias, acrophobia and glossophobia.
我其实还有两种恐惧症：恐高症和演讲恐惧症。
I guess that explains why you're afraid of flying, but public speaking is not that bad.
我想这解释了你为什么害怕飞行，但公开演讲没那么糟吧。
Are you kidding?
你在开玩笑吗？
When I get on stage, my palms start to sweat.
当我上台时，我的手心开始出汗。
I get really nervous and I can hardly speak.
我变得非常紧张，几乎说不出话。
Wow.
哇。
I must confess that I am a bit claustrophobic.
我必须承认我有点幽闭恐惧症。
I hate being in an elevator for more than five seconds.
我讨厌在电梯里待超过五秒钟。
We are such weirdos, right?
我们真是怪人，对吧？
All right.
好的。
So we've picked out a couple of different phrases today.
今天我们挑选了几个不同的短语。
Let's take a look at those now on Fluency Builder.
现在让我们在流利度训练中看看它们。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
So in the beginning of today's dialogue, the character said, I cannot wait to go to Europe,
在今天对话的开头，角色说：“我迫不及待想去欧洲，
but at the same time, I'm terrified.
但同时我又很害怕。”
So at the same time.
所以“同时”。
So in this case, we're saying that we are happy, but also we are scared.
在这种情况下，我们在说我们很开心，但同时也害怕。
So two things at once at the same time.
所以两件事同时发生。
Right.
对。
So this is a little bit different from when we talk about, I can do two things at the
这和我们说“我能同时做两件事”有点不同。
same time.
同时。
I can walk and chew gum.
我能边走路边嚼口香糖。
When we're talking about feelings or emotions, you say, you know, I'm happy, but at the same
当我们谈论感受或情绪时，你会说：“你知道，我很开心，但同时
time I'm also scared.
我也很害怕。”
That means that I have these two feelings and actually they're opposite feelings.
这意味着我有这两种感受，而且它们实际上是相反的感受。
Right.
对。
Exactly.
没错。
Usually they are opposite feelings.
通常它们是相反的感受。
So like you say, you're happy, but at the same time you're nervous.
所以就像你说你很开心，但同时也很紧张。
It's like saying on the other hand.
这就像说“另一方面”。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好的。
Now, when we talked about all these fears, we're afraid of flying, we are afraid of spiders.
现在，当我们谈论所有这些恐惧时，我们害怕飞行，我们害怕蜘蛛。
We describe them as a chronic fear.
我们描述它们为慢性恐惧。
Okay.
好的。
So this adjective chronic is very important because it has to do with time.
所以这个形容词“慢性”非常重要，因为它与时间有关。
Okay.
好的。
So I have a chronic fear of heights.
所以我有慢性的恐高症。
That means this is a fear I've always had.
这意味着这是我一直有的恐惧。
Okay.
好的。
And I will always have.
而且我会一直有。
Right.
对。
You can also say she has chronic back pain.
你也可以说“她有慢性背痛”。
That means it comes back again and again.
这意味着它反复发作。
It's not just one time.
不是一次性的。
It's all, it's some person's whole life.
它贯穿某人的一生。
Maybe not every day, but it comes back.
也许不是每天，但会反复出现。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
So that's, if you say you have a chronic something, you're explaining that you've had it for a
所以如果你说你有某种慢性问题，你在解释你已经有了它一段时间，
while or you will always have it.
或者你会一直有它。
Something usually very serious also.
通常也是比较严重的事情。
And going back to one of the phobias, we mentioned glossophobia and the other person said, well,
回到其中一种恐惧症，我们提到了演讲恐惧症，另一个人说：“嗯，
you know, public speaking is not that bad.
你知道，公开演讲没那么糟。”
It's not, it's not something to be so afraid of.
它不是什么值得那么害怕的事情。
And the other person replied by saying, are you kidding?
另一个人回答说：“你在开玩笑吗？”
Are you kidding?
你在开玩笑吗？
So this is actually a way of showing some sarcasm when you're talking because public
所以这实际上是一种表达讽刺的方式，当你说话时，因为公开
speaking is not that bad.
说话没那么糟糕。
The person wants to say, no, it is that bad.
这个人想说，不，就是那么糟糕。
It is awful.
太可怕了。
So are you kidding as a way to say, no, I totally disagree.
所以你说“你在开玩笑吧”是一种方式，表示“不，我完全不同意”。
Right.
对。
So you're being a little bit sarcastic, but at the same time, you're also acting a bit
所以你有点讽刺，但同时，你也表现得有点
surprised.
惊讶。
Like, I can't believe you said that.
就像，我不敢相信你说了这话。
Like if I said, I really liked the Twilight movies, Marco.
比如如果我说，我真的很喜欢《暮光之城》系列电影，马可。
Are you kidding?
你在开玩笑吧？
Those movies are terrible.
那些电影太烂了。
All right.
好吧。
So Marco does not agree with my opinion.
所以马可不同意我的观点。
All right.
好吧。
Now, when we're talking about public speaking, we mentioned that you get on stage.
现在，当我们谈论公开演讲时，我们提到你上台。
So this is very important because this is the action to get on stage and speak.
这非常重要，因为这是上台演讲的动作。
Okay.
好的。
So if you have a stage or maybe even you don't have a stage, but you're talking about performing
所以如果你有一个舞台，或者甚至没有舞台，但你在谈论在别人面前表演，
in front of other people, like a speech or a play, you say you get on stage and it's
比如演讲或戏剧，你说你上台，并且
important to remember this as a phrase.
记住这个短语很重要。
So whenever I get on stage, I start to sweat.
所以每当我上台，我就开始出汗。
Now you may want to add the, there you want to say to get on the stage, but it's not necessary.
现在你可能想加上“the”，说“上那个台”，但这不是必须的。
It's not incorrect, but the usual or let's say more correct form would just be, use the
这不算错，但通常或更正确的形式就是使用
phrase to get on stage.
短语“上台”。
When I get on stage, I get very nervous.
当我上台时，我非常紧张。
You don't have to say when I get on the stage.
你不必说“当我上那个台时”。
Or she's normally very shy, but when she gets on stage, she opens up and becomes very, very
或者她通常很害羞，但当她上台时，她变得开放，变得非常非常
talkative.
健谈。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好吧。
So that's all the phrases we've picked out for you.
这就是我们为你挑选的所有短语。
Let's listen to our dialogue one last time and we'll be right back.
让我们最后听一遍对话，然后我们马上回来。
Are you excited about your trip next month?
你对下个月的旅行感到兴奋吗？
Yes and no.
又兴奋又不兴奋。
I can't wait to go to Europe, but at the same time, I'm terrified.
我迫不及待想去欧洲，但同时，我又很害怕。
Why?
为什么？
Well, I have aerophobia.
嗯，我有飞行恐惧症。
I have a chronic fear of flying.
我有慢性飞行恐惧。
Oh really?
哦，真的吗？
I have an uncle who is also terrified of flying.
我有一个叔叔也害怕飞行。
It's not that bad though.
不过没那么糟糕。
I mean, it is pretty scary to be up in this big machine flying through the air at 700
我的意思是，坐在这个巨大的机器里以每小时700英里的速度在空中飞行确实很吓人。
miles per hour.
每小时700英里。
I actually have arachnophobia.
我其实有蜘蛛恐惧症。
You're scared of spiders?
你害怕蜘蛛？
I actually have two more phobias, acrophobia and glossophobia.
我其实还有两种恐惧症，恐高症和演讲恐惧症。
I guess that explains why you're afraid of flying, but public speaking is not that bad.
我想这解释了为什么你害怕飞行，但公开演讲没那么糟糕。
Are you kidding?
你在开玩笑吧？
When I get on stage, my palms start to sweat.
当我上台时，我的手掌开始出汗。
I get really nervous and I can hardly speak.
我非常紧张，几乎说不出话。
Well, I must confess that I am a bit claustrophobic.
嗯，我必须承认我有点幽闭恐惧症。
I hate being in an elevator for more than five seconds.
我讨厌在电梯里待超过五秒钟。
We are such weirdos, right?
我们真是怪人，对吧？
All right, so talking about all these phobias.
好吧，所以谈论所有这些恐惧症。
Now one of these phobias was actually made into a movie, I think in 1990.
其中一种恐惧症还被拍成了电影，我想是在1990年。
Arachnophobia, this very chronic fear of spiders.
蜘蛛恐惧症，这种对蜘蛛的慢性恐惧。
That's right.
没错。
I remember when I was younger and this movie came out, everybody started talking about
我记得我小时候这部电影上映时，每个人都开始谈论
how they were arachnophobic.
他们如何有蜘蛛恐惧症。
They had this horrible fear of spiders.
他们对蜘蛛有这种可怕的恐惧。
Did you ever see that movie?
你看过那部电影吗？
Yeah, of course.
是的，当然。
It was terrifying.
太吓人了。
Yes, it was supposedly some South American spider that made its way into the United States
是的，据说是一种南美蜘蛛，通过一个箱子、板条箱之类的东西
in a box, in a crate or something.
进入了美国。
Now, many people handle phobias differently.
现在，很多人以不同的方式应对恐惧症。
Do you have any phobia?
你有任何恐惧症吗？
Are you claustrophobic?
你有幽闭恐惧症吗？
Are you arachnophobic?
你有蜘蛛恐惧症吗？
I don't have any phobias and I'm not really afraid of anything.
我没有任何恐惧症，我什么都不怕。
So I'm pretty lucky that way, but I know a number of people who are afraid of heights,
所以在这方面我很幸运，但我认识很多人害怕高度，
acrophobic, and so that's pretty common.
有恐高症，这很常见。
And actually, if you look it up, you will find in the dictionary maybe hundreds of phobias,
实际上，如果你查一下，你会发现字典里可能有上百种恐惧症，
people who are afraid of open spaces, people who are afraid of closed spaces, or people
害怕开放空间的人，害怕封闭空间的人，或者
who are afraid of marriage.
害怕婚姻的人。
They even have a phobia determined for this type of person.
他们甚至为这类人定义了一种恐惧症。
So it's very interesting.
所以这很有趣。
Now, this is going to be a challenge.
现在，这将是一个挑战。
Why don't you look up a couple of different phobias and share it with us, maybe some of
你为什么不查几种不同的恐惧症，和我们分享一下，也许是一些
the craziest ones or the funniest ones or maybe the strangest ones you can find.
最疯狂、最有趣或最奇怪的。
That's right.
没错。
So look them up, share them with us.
所以查查它们，然后分享给我们。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是 EnglishPod.com。
All right.
好的。
We'll see you guys there.
我们到时候见。
Have a good one.
祝您愉快。